David Kirshon

kirshon.david@gmail.com • github.com/dmkirshon

linkedin.com/in/dmkirshon

Web Developer



Overview Web developer driven by solutions that focus on providing the best user experience while upholding code quality. Background in product management and systems design, using a holistic and logical approach toward complex problem solving.

Work History

Junior Software Developer

January 2023 - Present

NEWM - Global (Remote)

Developed Typescript Front-End, React.js, for the Artist-Portal Minimum Viable Product (MVP). Updated and Developed Sales Token Drop site for artist's new music releases.

- Collaborated with team to implement User Interface and Functional Requirements
- Reviewed multiple Github Pull Requests (PRs) for feature integration and code evaluation
- Investigated, Developed, and Integrated audio playback feature to incorporate HLS codec streams using third-party library and song detail API
- Peer coding with teammates for high priority issues and collaborative knowledge sharing

Software Development Intern

October 2022 - January 2023

NEWM - Global (Remote)

Developed Typescript Front-End, React.js, for the Artist-Portal Minimum Viable Product (MVP).

 Collaborated with Product, Software and Design team to implement new Button scheme and Song Library page from Figma design and ClickUp task requirements

Web Development Intern

August 2022 - October 2022

Beehivve - Vienna, Austria (Remote)

Developed Front-End, React.js, and Back-End, Firebase, for the web application platform.

- Implemented Firebase authentication for user security and web application functionality
- Upgraded and refactored to Firebase version 9 to improve code readability and build size
- Troubleshot and Fixed legacy website issue with invalid Google Firebase token

Chief Engineer

January 2019 - April 2021

NAVSEA Naval Undersea Warfare Center - Keyport, WA

Managed and directed a data transfer web application and storage system. In addition, directed the integration of 3rd party software applications on the system platform.

Systems Engineer

March 2017 - December 2018

NAVSEA Naval Undersea Warfare Center - Keyport, WA

Architected and managed a mapping and tracking combat system Java application. Supported the In-Service Engineering Agent for maintenance planning.

Projects

dmkirshon.github.io

HappilyEverAfterParty: A wedding website developed with Typescript and React. is Where's Narwhal: A Where's Waldo developed with Google Firebase and React. is **Shopping Cart:** A shopping web app utilizing a Web API, React.js, and React Router

Education University of Washington - Seattle, WA

December 2018

Master of Engineering in Industrial and Systems Engineering, GPA: 3.91

<u>University of California, San Diego - La Jolla, CA</u>

June 2014

B.S. Electrical Engineering: Electronic Devices and Materials, GPA: 3.33